A Finding Aid to the Holger Cahill Papers, 1910-1993, bulk 1910-1960, in the Archives of American Art AAA.cahiholg
Archives of American Art
- Works Progress Administration Federal Art Project, 1934-1970; Series 3; (Boxes 2-14, 18, MMs009; 10.75 linear ft.)
  - Allocations, 1935-1943, 1970; 3.6
    Allocation control cards were produced by the FAP's graphic arts division as a record of prints received in, and distributed by, the FAP's office in Washington D.C. for allocation and exhibition purposes. They give a number indicating the exhibition in which each print was included and a number indicating the total number of prints received (see General Correspondence, 1970, in this subseries). The cards are organized alphabetically by state.
    Also found here are tables of financial allotment statistics, printed material related to allocations of art work and a notebook entitled Congressional and D.C. Allocations.
    - Allocation Control Cards, California, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1106, Frame 1093-1186)
    - Allocation Control Cards, California, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 1106, Frame 1274-1279)
    - Allocation Control Cards, Colorado, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 1106, Frame 1187-1190)
    - Allocation Control Cards, Connecticut, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 1106, Frame 1191-1193)
    - Allocation Control Cards, Florida, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 1106, Frame 1194-1195)
    - Allocation Control Cards, Illinois, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 1106, Frame 1196-1217)
    - Allocation Control Cards, Kansas, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 1106, Frame 1218-1219)
    - Allocation Control Cards, Louisiana, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 1106, Frame 1220-1221)
    - Allocation Control Cards, Massachusetts, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 1106, Frame 1222-1250)
    - Allocation Control Cards, Michigan, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 1106, Frame 1251-1259)
    - Allocation Control Cards, Minnesota, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 1106, Frame 1260-1266)
    - Allocation Control Cards, New Hampshire, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 1106, Frame 1267-1269)
    - Allocation Control Cards, New Mexico, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 1106, Frame 1270-1272)
    - Allocation Control Cards, New York, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1106, Frame 1273)
    - Allocation Control Cards, New York, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 1106, Frame 1280-1419)
    - Allocation Control Cards, Ohio, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 1106, Frame 1420-1454)
    - Allocation Control Cards, Oregon, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 1106, Frame 1455-1456)
    - Allocation Control Cards, Pennsylvania, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 1106, Frame 1457-1492)
    - Allocation Control Cards, Rhode Island, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 1106, Frame 1493-1495)
    - Allocation Control Cards, Utah, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 1106, Frame 1496-1497)
    - Allocation Control Cards, Washington, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 1106, Frame 1498-1506)
    - Allocation Control Cards, Wisconsin, circa 1935-1941 (Reel 1106, Frame 1507-1512)
    - Allocation Statistics, 1935-1937 (Reel 1106, Frame 1061-1090)
    - Allocations to States, 1935 (Reel 1106, Frame 0875-0899)
    - Allocations to States, January-March 1936 (Reel 1106, Frame 0900-0931)
    - Allocations to States, April 1936 (Reel 1106, Frame 0932-0958)
    - Allocations to States, May-June 1936 (Reel 1106, Frame 0959-0989)
    - Allocations to States, July 1936 (Reel 1106, Frame 0990-1029)
    - Allocations to States, July 1936-January 1937 (Reel 1106, Frame 1030-1060)
    - Commercial Standards for Artists' Oil Paints, 1939 (Reel NDA 15, Frame 0668-0681)
    - Commercial Standards for Artists' Oil Paints, 1941-1943 (Reel 1106, Frame 0675-0704)
    - General Correspondence, 1936-1943 (Reel 1106, Frame 0655-0674)
    - General Correspondence, 1970 (Reel 1106, Frame 1092)
    - Notebook, Congressional and D.C. Allocations, 1936-1941 (Reel 1106, Frame 0705-0803)
    - Printed Material, 1936-1939 (Reel 1106, Frame 0804-0874)
  - Community Art Centers, 1934-1946; 3.7
    This subseries includes reports on various community art centers and news clippings about the art center in Curry County, Oregon.
    - News Clippings, Curry County Art Center, 1939-1941 (Reel 1107, Frame 0342-0382)
    - Reports, 1934 (Reel 1107, Frame 0220-0221)
    - Reports, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1107, Frame 0160-0204)
    - Reports, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 1107, Frame 0214-0219)
    - Reports, 1936 (Reel 1107, Frame 0222-0283)
    - Reports, 1937-1938 (Reel 1107, Frame 0284-0322)
    - Reports, 1938; (1 of 2) (Reel 1107, Frame 0205-0213)
    - Reports, 1938; (2 of 2) (Reel NDA 15, Frame 0866-0872)
    - Reports, 1939-1946 (Reel 1107, Frame 0323-0340)
  - FAP Divisions, 1935-1940; 3.8
    This subseries documents the activities of FAP divisions through typescripts, an interview transcript, memoranda, printed material and copies of poster designs.
    Art teaching typescripts include the following: Jacksonville Negro Art Gallery, Florida, Children's Art Gallery, Washington, D.C., Art and the Problem Child, Child Art Teaching, Saturday Morning Classes at the Kalamazoo Institute of Arts, Information Concerning District of Columbia Children's Drawings in Big Stone Gap Exhibition, The Artist Teaches, The Functions of Art Teaching in Education, The Works Program, and Child Art.
    Records relating to murals include a biographical sketch of the architect William Lescaze; a typescript entitled Statistical Note on Murals; and a booklet entitled Historical Murals in the Los Angeles County Hall of Records Board of Supervisors' Hearing Room. Records relating to posters include a typescript entitled List of Visual Aid and Other Training Material Produced for Military Establishments by Missouri Graphics Phase Units, 28 copies of poster designs, and a photograph of men in a poster composition room.
    - Art Teaching, 1936-1939 (Reel 1107, Frame 0738-0798)
    - Crafts, 1940 (Reel 1107, Frame 0799-0804)
    - Design Laboratory, 1935-1936 (Reel 1107, Frame 0805-0809)
    - Graphic Art, 1940 (Reel 1107, Frame 0810-0866)
    - Murals, 1936-1939 (Reel 1107, Frame 0867-0906)
    - Posters, circa 1935-1940 (Reel 1107, Frame 0907-0977)
  - Index of American Design, 1936-1947; 3.9
    The purpose of the Index of American Design was to compile a pictorial record of objects in the decorative, applied and folk arts, particularly objects of American origin. This subseries includes correspondence, memoranda, manuals, reports, typescripts, press releases, state reports primarily concerning Illinois projects, exhibition loan records, printed material and photographs of exhibitions and artwork, documenting that endeavor.
    Articles and reports include documents and manuals describing the form and function of the Index, and outlining related procedures to be followed. They also include typescripts about the Index including Recording American Design, [ The Shaker Portfolio], The Derivation and History of Weathervanes, A Short History of the Weathervane, The Eagle in American Design, American Traditions for Young People, and Notes on American Carvers and Carving. Also found here are press releases, notes, a list of collectors, memoranda, Art Circular No. 3 and a reprint entitled American Popular Art as Recorded in the Index of American Design by Erwin O. Christensen.
    Photographs include a bound portfolio of photographs of index plates representing artist renderings of Illinois objects, and a series of photographs depicting the process of making an index plate.
    - Articles and Reports, circa 1936-1941 (Reel 1107, Frame 1075-1234)
    - Articles and Reports, 1936 (Reel 1107, Frame 1235-1285)
    - Articles and Reports, 1937 (Reel 1107, Frame 1286-1310)
    - Articles and Reports, 1938 (Reel 1107, Frame 1311-1396)
    - Articles and Reports, 1941, 1947 (Reel 1107, Frame 1397-1412)
    - Correspondence and Memoranda, undated (Reel 1107, Frame 0979-0985)
    - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1936 (Reel 1107, Frame 0993-1058)
    - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1937, 1940 (Reel 1107, Frame 1059-1068)
    - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1941-1942; (1 of 2) (Reel 1107, Frame 1069-1074)
    - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1941-1942; (2 of 2) (Reel 1107, Frame 0986-0992)
    - Lists of Artwork/Receipts for Exhibition Loans, 1936 (Reel 5292, Frame 0683-0730)
    - Notes, circa 1936-1942; (1 of 2) (Reel 1108, Frame 0263-0304)
    - Notes, circa 1936-1942; (2 of 2) (Reel 5292, Frame 0672-0682)
    - State Reports, 1942 (Reel 1107, Frame 1413-1438)
    - State Reports, Illinois, 1942; (1 of 2) (Reel 1107, Frame 1439-1503)
    - State Reports, Illinois, 1942; (2 of 2) (Reel 1108, Frame 0001-0262)
    - Portfolio of Index Plates from Illinois, 1942 (Reel 1108, Frame 0554-0938)
    - Printed Material, Booklet The Silkscreen Process, 1941 (Reel 1108, Frame 0508-0553)
    - Photographs, Exhibitions, 1938-1939 (Reel 1108, Frame 0305-0328)
    - Photographs, "Making an Index Plate,", circa 1936-1942 (Reel 1108, Frame 0367-0423)
    - Photographs, Objects, circa 1936-1942; (1 of 3) (Reel 1108, Frame 0329-0366)
    - Photographs, Objects, circa 1936-1942; (2 of 3) (Reel 1108, Frame 0424-0491)
    - Photographs, Objects, circa 1936-1942; (3 of 3) (Reel 1108, Frame 0506-0507)
    - Photographs, Shaker Buildings and People, circa 1936-1942 (Reel 1108, Frame 0492-0505)
  - Exhibitions, 1935-1942; 3.10
    This subseries consists of reports on exhibitions, shipping receipts for artwork, news clippings, exhibition catalogs, and records relating to the FAP Exhibition of Contemporary Art at the 1939-1940 New York World's Fair.
    Records of the New York World'd Fair exhibition include correspondence, typescripts, memoranda, a budget plan, a list of sculptors employed by the FAP in New York City, prospectuses for artists, a calendar of events, press releases, printed material and photographs.
    - Catalogs, 1936-1939 (Reel 1107, Frame 584-683)
    - Childrens' Art Exhibitions, 1937-1939 (Reel 1107, Frame 539-563)
    - New York World's Fair Exhibition (1939-1940), 1935-1938 (Reel 5292, Frame 0732-0778)
    - New York World's Fair Exhibition (1939-1940), 1938-1939 (Reel 5292, Frame 0780-0839)
    - New York World's Fair Exhibition (1939-1940) (Reel 5292, Frame 0841-0888)
    - New York World's Fair Exhibition (1939-1940) (Reel 5292, Frame 0890-0950)
    - New York World's Fair Exhibition (1939-1940) (Reel 1107, Frame 564-583)
    - Exhibition Reports, 1936-1942 (Reel 1107, Frame 509-538)
    - News Clippings, 1936-1939 (Reel 1107, Frame 684-700)
  - Other New Deal Art Projects, 1935-1942; 3.11
    This subseries contains records related to two other New Deal art projects: the Office of Emergency Management (OEM) Art Project and the Treasury Department Art Project (TDAP). Included here are one bulletin relating to the former and four letters and a series of bulletins relating to the latter.
    - OEM Art Bulletin No.1, 1942 (Reel 1109, Frame 1068-1069)
    - TDAP Correspondence, 1935 (Reel 1109, Frame 1014-1022)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 1, March 1, 1935 (Reel 5290, Frame 0583-0595)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 2, April 1, 1935 (Reel 5290, Frame 0596-0609)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 3, May-June 1935 (Reel 5290, Frame 0610-0625)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 4, July-August 1935 (Reel 5290, Frame 0626-0641)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 5, September 1935 (Reel 5290, Frame 0642-0662)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 6, October-November 1935 (Reel 5290, Frame 0663-0678)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 7, December 1935 (Reel 5290, Frame 0679-0696)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 8, January-February 1936 (Reel 5290, Frame 0697-0732)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 9, March-May 1936 (Reel 5290, Frame 0733-0756)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 10, June-August 1936 (Reel 5290, Frame 0757-0776)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 11, September 1936-February 1937 (Reel 5290, Frame 0777-0795)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 12, February 1937 (Reel 5290, Frame 0796-0812)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 13, March-June 1937 (Reel 5290, Frame 0813-0829)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 14, July 1937-January 1938 (Reel 5290, Frame 0830-0862)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 15, March 1938 (Reel 5290, Frame 0863-0873)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 16, circa April-August 1938 (Reel 5290, Frame 0874-0881)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 17, September 1938 (Reel 5290, Frame 0882-0898)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 18, February 1939 (Reel 5290, Frame 0899-0918)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 19, June 1939 (Reel 5290, Frame 0919-0948)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 20, November 1939 (Reel 5290, Frame 0949-0965)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 21, March 1940 (Reel 5290, Frame 0966-0981)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 22, September 1940 (Reel 5290, Frame 0982-1003)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 23, March 1941 (Reel 5290, Frame 1004-1010)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 24, May 1941 (Reel 5290, Frame 1011-1016)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 8 (duplicate), January-February 1936 (Reel 1109, Frame 1070-1105)
    - TDAP Bulletin No. 10 (duplicate), June-August 1936 (Reel 1109, Frame 1106-1125)
  - Publicity and Printed Material, 1934-1944, 1961; 3.12
    This subseries contains printed material relating to the WPA/FAP as well as material used for publicity including transcripts of lectures and essays (some with hand-written notations), news clippings, press releases, and publications. For additional material of this type see Series 4: Writings, Lectures and Speeches and Series 8: Printed Material. Additional press releases can be found in 3.13: Scrapbooks.
    - Brochure, Purposes, Functions, Techniques: Federal Art Project Exhibitions, undated; (see MMs009) (Reel 3482, Frame 1134-1153)
    - Government Acts and Resolutions, 1935-1939 (Reel NDA 15, Frame 0341-0373)
    - Government Acts and Resolutions, 1939 (Reel 1109, Frame 0255-0437)
    - Lectures and Essays, undated (Reel NDA 15, Frame 0520-0531)
    - Lectures and Essays, 1936-circa 1940 (Reel 1108, Frame 0942-1070)
    - Lectures and Essays, 1937; (1 of 2) (Reel NDA 15, Frame 0494-0503)
    - Lectures and Essays, 1937; (2 of 2) (Reel NDA 15, Frame 0602-0605)
    - Lectures and Essays, 1941; (1 of 3) (Reel NDA 15, Frame 0509-0519)
    - Lectures and Essays, 1941; (2 of 3) (Reel NDA 15, Frame 0616-0632)
    - Lectures and Essays, 1941; (3 of 3) (Reel NDA 15, Frame 0638-0644)
    - List of Magazine Articles on FAP, 1940 (Reel 5294, Frame 0789-0798)
    - Press Releases, 1936-1939, undated (Reel 1108, Frame 1071-1101)
    - Press Releases, 1941 (Reel NDA 15, Frame 0633-0637)
    - Press Releases, 1942 (Reel NDA 15, Frame 0655-0656)
    - News Clippings, undated; (1 of 4) (Reel 1108, Frame 1108-1124)
    - News Clippings, undated; (2 of 4) (Reel 1108, Frame 1318)
    - News Clippings, undated; (3 of 4) (Reel 1108, Frame 1320-1324)
    - News Clippings, undated; (4 of 4) (Reel 1108, Frame 1327-1332)
    - News Clippings, 1934 (Reel 1108, Frame 1316-1317)
    - News Clippings, 1935; (1 of 2) (Reel 1108, Frame 1126-1149)
    - News Clippings, 1935; (2 of 2) (Reel 1108, Frame 1333-1337)
    - News Clippings, 1936; (1 of 2) (Reel 1108, Frame 1150-1231)
    - News Clippings, 1936; (2 of 2) (Reel 1108, Frame 1338-1367)
    - News Clippings, 1937; (1 of 2; see also Box 18) (Reel 1108, Frame 1232-1257)
    - News Clippings, 1937; (2 of 2; see also Box 18) (Reel 1108, Frame 1368-1401)
    - News Clippings, 1938; (1 of 3) (Reel 1108, Frame 1258-1277)
    - News Clippings, 1938; (2 of 3) (Reel 1108, Frame 1319)
    - News Clippings, 1938; (3 of 3) (Reel 1109, Frame 0001-0107)
    - News Clippings, 1939; (1 of 3) (Reel 1108, Frame 1278-1294)
    - News Clippings, 1939; (2 of 3) (Reel 1108, Frame 1325-1326)
    - News Clippings, 1939; (3 of 3) (Reel 1109, Frame 0108-0156)
    - News Clippings, 1940 (Reel 1108, Frame 1295)
    - News Clippings, 1942 (Reel 1108, Frame 1296-1314)
    - News Clippings, 1944 (Reel 1109, Frame 0157-0158)
    - News Clippings, 1939-1943, 1961, undated (Reel NDA 15, Frame 0995-1030)
    - Publications, circa 1939 (Reel 1109, Frame 0160-0254)
    - Publications, 1939 (Reel 1109, Frame 0438-0473)
    - Publications, 1940; (1 of 2) (Reel 1109, Frame 0474-0598)
    - Publications, 1940; (2 of 2) (Reel 1109, Frame 0683-0737)
    - Publications, 1941 (Reel 1109, Frame 0738-0963)
    - Publications, 1942 (Reel 1109, Frame 0964-1012)
    - Sunday Night Art Forum Announcements, undated (Reel 1108, Frame 1102-1107)
    - WPA Technical Problems of the Artist Series, circa 1938 (Reel 5296, Frame 0747-0811)
    - WPA Technical Series, 1940, undated (Reel 1109, Frame 0599-0682)
    - WPA Technical Series, 1941 (Reel 5296, Frame 0817-0862)
  - Scrapbooks, 1936-1939; 3.13
    This subseries contains three scrapbooks: Scrapbook I contains primarily press releases from the WPA Works Program as well as state progress reports, exhibition catalogs, and miscellaneous printed material. It includes photos of sculptor Jose Ruiz de Rivera and a New York Cityscape by Berenice Abbott. Scrapbook II contains news clippings and printed material concerning FAP conferences and the Index of American Design. Scrapbook III contains news clippings, exhibition catalogs and miscellaneous printed material. It also conains six photos of art centers and exhibitions, six photos of art classes and seven photos of artwork.
    - Scrapbook I, 1935 (Reel 5292, Frame 1466-1494)
    - Scrapbook I, 1936 (Reel 5293, Frame 0005-0024)
    - Scrapbook I, January-May 1937 (Reel 5293, Frame 0025-0061)
    - Scrapbook I, June 1-15, 1937 (Reel 5293, Frame 0062-0092)
    - Scrapbook I, June 16-30, 1937 (Reel 5293, Frame 0093-0129)
    - Scrapbook I, July 1-15, 1937 (Reel 5293, Frame 0130-0152)
    - Scrapbook I, July 16-31, 1937 (Reel 5293, Frame 0153-0184)
    - Scrapbook I, August 1937 (Reel 5293, Frame 0185-0218)
    - Scrapbook I, September 1-15, 1937 (Reel 5293, Frame 0219-0233)
    - Scrapbook I, September 16-30, 1937 (Reel 5293, Frame 0234-0262)
    - Scrapbook I, October 1937 (Reel 5293, Frame 0263-0302)
    - Scrapbook I, November 1-10, 1937 (Reel 5293, Frame 0303-0338)
    - Scrapbook I, November 11-19, 1937 (Reel 5293, Frame 0340-0364)
    - Scrapbook I, November 20-30, 1937 (Reel 5293, Frame 0365-0383)
    - Scrapbook I, December 1-8, 1937 (Reel 5293, Frame 0384-0412)
    - Scrapbook I, December 9-21, 1937 (Reel 5293, Frame 0413-0434)
    - Scrapbook I, December 22-31, 1937 (Reel 5293, Frame 0435-0461)
    - Scrapbook I, January 1-12, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 0462-0493)
    - Scrapbook I, January 13-18, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 0494-0520)
    - Scrapbook I, January 19-27, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 0521-0559)
    - Scrapbook I, January 28-31, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 0560-0587)
    - Scrapbook I, February 1-15, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 0588-0642)
    - Scrapbook I, February 16-28, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 0643-0683)
    - Scrapbook I, March 1-10, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 0684-0723)
    - Scrapbook I, March 11-23, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 0724-0772)
    - Scrapbook I, March 25-31, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 0773-0801)
    - Scrapbook I, April 1-21, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 0802-0844)
    - Scrapbook I, April 22-30, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 0845-0882)
    - Scrapbook I, May 1-10, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 0883-0921)
    - Scrapbook I, May 11-16, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 0922-0956)
    - Scrapbook I, May 17-31, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 0957-0993)
    - Scrapbook I, June 1-15, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 0994-1024)
    - Scrapbook I, June 16-30, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 1025-1056)
    - Scrapbook I, July 1-18, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 1057-1113)
    - Scrapbook I, July 19-31, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 1114-1146)
    - Scrapbook I, August 1-10, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 1147-1177)
    - Scrapbook I, August 11-20, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 1178-1219)
    - Scrapbook I, August 21-31, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 1220-1247)
    - Scrapbook I, September 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 1248-1315)
    - Scrapbook I, October 1-21, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 1316-1346)
    - Scrapbook I, October 22-31, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 1347-1370)
    - Scrapbook I, November 1-10, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 1371-1405)
    - Scrapbook I, November 14-20, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 1406-1425)
    - Scrapbook I, November 21-30, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 1426-1453)
    - Scrapbook I, December 1-14, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 1454-1500)
    - Scrapbook I, December 15-31, 1938 (Reel 5293, Frame 1501-1541)
    - Scrapbook I, January 1-15, 1939 (Reel 5294, Frame 0004-0030)
    - Scrapbook I, January 16-24, 1939 (Reel 5294, Frame 0031-0056)
    - Scrapbook I, January 25-31, 1939 (Reel 5294, Frame 0057-0093)
    - Scrapbook I, February 1-15, 1939 (Reel 5294, Frame 0094-0132)
    - Scrapbook I, February 16-28, 1939 (Reel 5294, Frame 0133-0170)
    - Scrapbook I, March 1-14, 1939 (Reel 5294, Frame 0171-0195)
    - Scrapbook I, March 15-21, 1939 (Reel 5294, Frame 0196-0222)
    - Scrapbook I, March 22-31, 1939 (Reel 5294, Frame 0223-0249)
    - Scrapbook I, March-April 1939 (Reel 5294, Frame 0250-0291)
    - Scrapbook I, April 1-11, 1939 (Reel 5294, Frame 0292-0326)
    - Scrapbook I, April 12-30, 1939 (Reel 5294, Frame 0327-0357)
    - Scrapbook I, May 1-14, 1939 (Reel 5294, Frame 0358-0396)
    - Scrapbook I, May 15-21, 1939 (Reel 5294, Frame 0397-0427)
    - Scrapbook I, May 22-31, 1939 (Reel 5294, Frame 0428-0469)
    - Scrapbook I, June 1-12, 1939 (Reel 5294, Frame 0470-0494)
    - Scrapbook I, June 13-30, 1939 (Reel 5294, Frame 0495-0534)
    - Scrapbook I, July 1939 (Reel 5294, Frame 0535-0565)
    - Scrapbook II, 1936-1939 (Reel 5294, Frame 0566-0638)
    - Scrapbook III, 1937-1939; (see Box 18) (Reel 5294, Frame 0639-0787)
  - Photographs, circa 1935-1948; 3.14
    This series begins with photographs of WPA artists, regional directors, and art administrators. The individuals pictured include: Lucienne Bloch, Karl Knaths, Donald J. Bear, Max Spivak, Increase Robinson, F. C. Harrington, Russell C. Parr, George G. Thorp, Eve Alsman Fuller, R. Bruce Inverarity, Eleanor Roosevelt with R. Bruce Inverarity, Florence Kerr, Robert Armstrong Andrews, Richard C. Morrison, Jacob Baker, Holger Cahill and Jacob Baker, Joseph Danysh, C. Adolph Glassgold, Thomas C. Parker, Elizabeth Olds, Milton Horn, Juan Sanchez, Patricino Barela, Sam Brown, Harry Hopkins and Holger Cahill, Stanton MacDonald Wright at the dedication of the Father Garces monument, John Palo-Kangas, Seminole Indians at the opening of the Miami Federal Galleries, Ellen Woodward with Thomas C. Parker, and Holger Cahill with Duncan Phillips and Harry L. Hopkins.
    Also found here are three photograph "albums." Photograph Album I contains photos of artwork, installations, and Shaker furniture and buildings. Photograph Album II contains photos of artists, art classes, and artwork in addition to printed material. Photograph Album III contains photos of posters and murals, group activities and classes relating to the WPA and defense.
    This series also contains thirteen photographs of "Changing New York" by Berenice Abbott. The remainder of the series consists of FAP photos of art classes, gallery installations, state art centers and staff and artwork, arranged by state.
    For additional FAP photographs see 3.1 (for photographs of FAP administrators), 3.2. (for photographs of Artists), 3.8 (for photographs related to the Index of American Design), 3.10 (for photographs from the 1939-1940 World's Fair) and 3.13 (for photographs from FAP scrapbooks).
    - Adminstrator Photos, circa 1936-1938; (includes photograph of Eleanor Roosevelt, 3/25/38) (Reel 1109, Frame 1126-1144)
    - Artist, Regional Director, and Art Administrator Photos, circa 1937-1939 (Reel 1109, Frame 1147-1197)
    - Berenice Abbott Photos, 1936-1938 (Reel 1109, Frame 1198-1224)
    - Berenice Abbott, Negatives and Copy Prints, 1936-1938 (Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
    - Photograph Album I, circa 1936 (Reel 5296, Frame 1021-1354)
    - Photograph Album I, cont., circa 1936 (Reel 5297, Frame 0004-0331)
    - Photograph Album II, circa 1937; (see Box 18) (Reel 5297, Frame 0332-0418)
    - Photograph Album III, circa 1936-1941 (Reel 5297, Frame 0419-0478)
    - Alabama Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (1 of 2) (Reel 1109, Frame 1225-1231)
    - Alabama Photographs, circa 1935-1941; (2 of 2) (Reel 5297, Frame 0481-0484)